dymoendicia.com 2015-12-07

# Privacy Policy | Endicia

Your privacy is extremely important to us, and we are committed to protecting your privacy rights. This policy describes how we treat your personal and non-personal information that is collected when you navigate our website, use our products, and/or contact us. The Endicia website is owned and operated by PSI Systems, Inc.

This policy is effective as of June 3, 2013. Updated November 15, 2015. 

## Information Collection and Use

  1. **When You Visit the Endicia Website**

When you visit and browse through our website, we automatically gather and store the following information about your visit (that does not identify you personally): 

    * The Internet domain (for example, "xyzcompany.com") and IP address (number assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet) from which you access our website 
    * The type of browser and operating system used to access our website 
    * The date and time you access our website 
    * The web pages visited 
    * The Internet address of the website you are visiting from, if any 

We use this information to make our site more useful to our visitors. The information helps us learn about the number of visitors to the different sections of our site, what information is of most and least interest to our visitors, and technical information that will enhance the ease-of-use, such as the types of technology our visitors use and system performance or problem areas. 

We may use persistent cookies and session cookies to maintain your data while you sign up for our service and while you purchase products from our online store. These cookies do not identify you personally. Session cookies are released as soon as you complete or terminate your sign-up or purchase. Persistent cookies are released when you delete them from your computer or automatically deleted after one year. 

We only collect information that identifies you personally when you choose to share it with us by signing up for our service, purchasing products from our online store, or sending us an email message. 

  2. **When You Sign Up For Our Service**

To use Endicia products, you must register via our web-enabled online registration form. The U.S. Postal Service® must approve your registration. During the registration process, the following information is collected: 

    * Your name, title, and company name 
    * Your physical and mailing addresses, your telephone and fax numbers, and your email address 
    * The Post Office™ location you will use most often to send your mail 
    * Your credit card information, including number, type, expiration date, and billing address 
    * Your checking account number and bank routing number if you choose to pay for postage via direct debit from your checking account 

This information is securely electronically transmitted to the U.S. Postal Service to complete the registration process. This information is primarily used to register you as an Endicia user, as well as for future account management activities associated with your normal day-to-day activities. 

  3. **When You Purchase Products at Our Online Store**

We collect the following information when you make a purchase at our online store: 

    * Your name and company name 
    * Your credit card information, including number, type, expiration date, cardholder name, and billing address 
    * Your shipping address, your telephone number, and your email address 

This information is used to charge your credit card for store purchases and to fulfill your order. It is shared with our payment processors and companies that fulfill and ship our orders, with whom we have confidentiality agreements. It may be stored to provide customer support on your orders. 

  4. **When You Send Us an Email**

We provide technical and pre-sales support through email. We include links on our website for you to send us email. If you send us an email message that includes personal information, we will use that information to respond to your inquiry. We will preserve the content of your email, your email address, and our response, so that we can more efficiently handle any follow-up questions. 

Please remember that email is not necessarily secure against interception. If your communication is very sensitive or includes information such as your bank account number, charge card number, or social security number, do not use email, but call us instead. 

  5. **When You Purchase Postage With Endicia**

When you purchase postage using Endicia, we collect information about the amount and date of your postage purchase. 

    * If you use a credit card for postage payment, we share your credit card information with our credit card processor to authorize and process your payment every time you purchase postage 
    * If you use a checking account for postage payment, we share your checking account information with our direct debit processor to authorize and process your payment every time you purchase postage. 
  6. **When You Print Postage With Endicia**

When you print postage using Endicia, we collect the following information: 

    * The date and time of the transaction 
    * The destination ZIP Code™ 
    * The rate category of each indicium created 
    * The amount of postage printed 

The primary purpose of this information is to generate valid postage indicia in compliance with U.S. Postal Service rules. 

When you use Endicia software to print electronic USPS Tracking, Signature Confirmation™, or the electronic Priority Mail Express® label, we also collect complete return and destination address data, package descriptions, reference IDs, and delivery statuses for each label you print. We maintain this information for your accounting and reporting purposes in the account management section of our website. 

  7. **When You Provide Us Information to Download the Endicia XML Specifications for PC or Mac:**

When you provide us with information to download Endicia's XML specifications for PC or Mac, we collect the following information: 

    * Your name and email address 
    * Your organization name, job title, phone number, and website URL 

This information is collected to identify you as an integrator. It may be stored to contact you and provide support for your integration.

  8. **When You Provide Us With Information to Access the Endicia Label Server API:**

When you provide us with information to access the Endicia Label Server API, we collect the following information:

    * Your name and email address 
    * Your organization name, job title, phone number, and website URL 
    * Your mailing address 
    * Various facts about your current needs and solutions 

The information is used to electronically enter into a Non-Disclosure Agreement between you and Endicia. It is also collected to identify you as an integrator and may be stored to contact you and provide support for your integration.

  9. **When You Provide Us With Information on Your U.S. Postal Service Rep Portal Account:**

When you provide us with information on your U.S. Postal Service Rep Portal Account, we collect the following information: 

    * Your name 
    * Your organization name, job title, phone number, and fax number 
    * Your mailing address 
    * Your physical address 

This information is used to contact you and ship marketing items ordered through this portal. It is also collected to identify you as a U.S. Postal Service Representative.

## Security Practices for the Information Collected

Endicia will safeguard any information you share with us according to strict standards of security and confidentiality. To ensure your personal information remains confidential, the information is sent via a secure session established by Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) or equivalent technology. These technologies encrypt and protect your personal information to guard against unauthorized access. 

## Privacy Act Notice

As a service provider to the U.S. Postal Service, we follow the privacy requirements of the U.S. Postal Service Privacy Policy and the Privacy Act, which protects the personal information that we hold. The Privacy Act provides protections for your personal information, including how this information is collected, used, disclosed, stored, and discarded. Your information will be used to provide you with requested products, services, and/or information. Collection of information is authorized by 39 USC 401, 402, and 404. Providing this information is voluntary, but if you do not provide it, we may not process your transaction. We do not disclose information about consumers without their consent except to facilitate the transaction, to act on your behalf or request, or as legally required. 

## Information Sharing

Endicia does not rent, sell, or trade your personal information with anyone for marketing purposes. We only share your information with third parties as follows: 

  1. We share certain information about you with the U.S. Postal Service in compliance with its regulatory oversight of our postage service. For more information on the U.S. Postal Service privacy policy, please see its [Privacy Policy](http://about.usps.com/who-we-are/privacy-policy/privacy-policy-highlights.htm). 
  2. We may share your information if it is subpoenaed in legal proceedings, requested by a government agency, needed in an investigation; or in order to protect our rights, property, or safety or the rights, property, or safety of our users or others (e.g., a consumer reporting agency for fraud protection); or as required by law. 
  3. Endicia may share part of your information with our affiliates if you signed up with Endicia using one of their affiliate links, or with other Endicia customers if you identified them as a referrer to our service. Endicia will not share any of your personal information with the referrer or affiliate. 
  4. Endicia may provide information to trusted partners or contractors working on our behalf, subject to confidentiality agreements that bar their use of this information for their own purposes. 
  5. If you have a DYMO Stamps account, Endicia may share certain information about your DYMO Stamps account, including your contact information, billing transactions, and usage data with DYMO Corporation. DYMO's usage of this information is governed by DYMO Corporation's Privacy Policy. For more information on DYMO's Privacy Policy, please visit [www.dymo.com](http://www.dymo.com/). 
  6. In the case of a merger or acquisition of our company, service, or assets, Endicia may share your information with the other company and will notify you on this site if your information is to be transferred. 
  7. Endicia contracts with an online partner to help manage and optimize our Internet business and communications. We use the services of this company to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our website. To do this, we use web beacons and cookies provided by our marketing company. The type of information we collect includes information about your browser and which technologies you use, where in the world you are located, and how you interact with our site, including the product codes you use, the price for merchandise you purchase, and which pages you visit. We do not collect any personally identifiable information in this process. By supplementing our records, this information helps us learn things such as what pages are most attractive to our visitors, which of our products is of the most interest to our customers, and what kinds of offers our customers like to see. Our marketing partner logs the information coming from our site on our behalf, and we control how that data may and may not be used. If you do not want to help us learn how to improve our site, products, offers, and marketing strategy, you can opt-out of these website analysis tools by clicking these links: 
    * Adobe Analytics: <http://www.adobe.com/privacy.html>
    * AdRoll: <http://www.adroll.com/about/privacy>
    * Bizo: <http://www.bizo.com/privacy_policy>
    * Google Analytics Data Privacy & Security: <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>
    * Google Analytics Opt-out: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>
    * Quantcast: <http://www.quantcast.com/privacy>
    * Trade Desk: <http://www.thetradedesk.com/privacy-policy>
  8. Endicia also contracts with a company called Demandbase Data Management Platform. The Demandbase Data Management Platform (“DMP”) is the proprietary data platform linking over 3 Billion IP Addresses to 6.6 Million Companies worldwide. The DMP provides Audience Segments as well as B2B Company Profiles and Premium Information on an IP by IP basis to power the Demandbase Company-Targeted Advertising. This solution does not utilize cookies and so Demandbase does not collect, store, or share any contact or other data about individuals or data subjects. As a result, the DMP contains no Personally Identifiable Information. For more information visit their privacy policy: <http://www.demandbase.com/who-is-demandbase/about-demandbase/privacy>. 

With your consent, Endicia may from time to time communicate information to you as a consumer regarding our services, products, announcements, or special offers or from one of our partners. In cases where the communication concerns one of our partners, only we (or our agents under confidentiality agreements) will communicate with you directly, and we will not release your information to our partners. 

If you have a business account with us, you may opt-out of these communications by notifying us at the email address listed below.

## Child Privacy

You must be at least 18 years of age to use this site for the purchase of goods or services. If you are under the age of 18, you are welcome to browse this site, but you are not permitted to provide information to us or to make any purchases.

## Your Access to Information Collected

Endicia makes every effort to ensure the data we collect is accurate, complete, and timely. You may review your account information online by logging into your account on the account management section of our website. You may update your information using the account management website, or you may contact us to correct or delete any of your data.

If you have any questions or suggestions about our privacy policy, or if you would like to opt-out of communications from us, please contact us at:

650-321-2640 x140

**Endicia**  
IBIP Privacy  
278 Castro Street  
Mountain View, CA 94041-1204

## Privacy Policy Changes

Endicia may from time to time update its privacy policy. If we make changes to our privacy policy, the new privacy policy and new effective date will be posted on this website. 

© Copyright 2015, Endicia. All rights reserved.
